<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Rob Hunter</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Rob Hunter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 Rob Hunter</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital and Climate in the Critique of the State</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/06/06/capital-and-climate-in-the-critique-of-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/06/06/capital-and-climate-in-the-critique-of-the-state/</guid>
      <description>My contribution to Legal Form&amp;lsquo;s state debate series focuses on catastrophic climate change. A preview:
 The constitutional obduracy of capitalist states renders them inappropriate vehicles, at best, for ecosocial transformation. Moreover, the mutual presupposition of the capitalist state and the capitalist economy (so that it is inappropriate to speak of the one and not the other) means that new forms of resource management, labour relations, and production coordination cannot simply be legislated into existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kavanaugh and the Constitutionalization of Politics</title>
      <link>/posts/2018/10/05/kavanaugh-and-the-practice-of-constitutionalism-in-global-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018/10/05/kavanaugh-and-the-practice-of-constitutionalism-in-global-context/</guid>
      <description>A longer version of this essay was posted on Legal Form on October 9, 2018.
(Updated October 7)
Contradiction is the recurring motif in the current Supreme Court nomination battle. Nowhere is this clearer than in the simultaneous magnification and diminution of the trauma of sexual violence. With their insistence that accusers&amp;rsquo; accounts must be examined closely for any possible defect, and that the accused must never not have our sympathy, conservatives manage both to obsess over sexual assault and to trivialize it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Constitutionalism: An Archaic System</title>
      <link>/posts/2017/05/01/an-archaic-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017/05/01/an-archaic-document/</guid>
      <description>Fredric Jameson, An American Utopia: Dual Power and the Universal Army:
 [W]hoever interrogates political possibility in the United States must necessarily confront the unique problems posed by that counterrevolutionary document&amp;hellip;
 Donald Trump, as quoted in the Guardian:
 “It’s a very rough system,” he said. “It’s an archaic system … It’s really a bad thing for the country.”
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest Aggregation, Preference Expression, and the Democrats</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/11/29/interest-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/11/29/interest-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Many elite liberals and Democratic operatives are embracing the bogus narrative that Hillary Clinton&#39;s defeat resulted from a failure to pursue a median voter who is imagined to be an economically distressed white worker (and is believed to be drawn to Trump&#39;s racism and xenophobia). There are several useful critiques of this line of thought out there &amp;ndash; the most potent being this LARB squib by Katherine Franke. What I want to consider briefly in this post (and hopefully more thoroughly in a later post) is what the emergence of this line says about how prominent Democratic politicians and their epigones think about politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pathologies of Right-Wing Libertarianism</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/10/05/the-pathologies-of-right-wing-libertarianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/10/05/the-pathologies-of-right-wing-libertarianism/</guid>
      <description>I have a new essay on the theoretical foundations of contemporary right-wing libertarianism up at Jacobin:
 By elevating capitalist rationality above all other forms of social organizing, and by dismissing the public authority of democratic institutions as provisional and limited at best, libertarians advocate for conservatism, for capitulation to elites, and ultimately for the rejection of political activity. Libertarian political theory is in fact a potent form of anti-politics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut-and-Run Liberalism</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/03/18/cut-and-run-liberalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/03/18/cut-and-run-liberalism/</guid>
      <description>I wrote on President Obama&#39;s selection of Merrick Garland as his Supreme Court nominee for Jacobin:
{% blockquote %}
Obama’s decision to nominate Garland foreshadows the politics of accommodation likely to be pursued by the presumptive Democratic nominee. Both Obama and Clinton personify American liberalism — an ideology premised on a disdain for political antagonism and a fear of unresolved disagreement.
The nomination of Merrick Garland is only the latest illustration of this tendency in liberalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Thoughts on the Current Constitutional Showdown</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/02/23/a-few-thoughts-on-the-current-constitutional-showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/02/23/a-few-thoughts-on-the-current-constitutional-showdown/</guid>
      <description>It was revealed today that Senate Republicans have enough party discipline to refuse to hold confirmation hearings for any nominee put forward by President Obama to fill the current vacancy on the Supreme Court.
It will be objected that McConnell&#39;s blanket refusal is a challenge to Obama&#39;s constitutional legitimacy and authority &amp;ndash; and so it is. Indeed, that is rather the point. The Republicans not only wish to portray Obama as a lame duck; they are asserting that any nominee put forward by Obama will be substantively illegitimate, no matter the fact that Obama is formally authorized by the constitutional text to nominate a justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Court After Scalia</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/02/15/the-supreme-court-after-scalia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/02/15/the-supreme-court-after-scalia/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve written about the future of the Supreme Court after Scalia over at Jacobin. Here&#39;s a taste:
 We should not chase after the fantasy of exploiting Scalia’s absence to reconstitute a liberal-majority Court — and not merely because any possible Democratic president in 2017 is likely to lack the political support needed for successful judicial appointments.
  We should instead explore and promote options that would subordinate the Supreme Court to political control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free vs. Open Source Software</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/02/05/free-vs-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/02/05/free-vs-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about free vs. open source software for Jacobin. Unlike a lot of writing on the subject, I quite deliberately tried to use as few acronyms as possible&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Without Politics</title>
      <link>/posts/2015/11/13/progress-without-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015/11/13/progress-without-politics/</guid>
      <description>I reviewed Notorious RBG: The Life and Times of Ruth Bader Ginsburg for Jacobin. Here&#39;s a taste:
 The Warren Court’s victories in taking on segregation, civil liberties restrictions, and invasive policing tactics prompted a legalistic turn in liberal political strategy. Judicial review — once regarded as a tool of reaction and a barrier to reform — became more attractive as a method for achieving political goals. The Supreme Court’s higher political profile turned judicial appointments into valuable prizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worse Regimes</title>
      <link>/posts/2015/03/30/worse-regimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015/03/30/worse-regimes/</guid>
      <description>Frances Stonor Saunders&#39;s impressive LRB piece on Eric Hobsbawm&#39;s file at MI5 is well-worth reading, but it ends with an odd coda:
 The two sides in the Cold War, finding each other irresistible, ended up in a contrapuntal relationship where, as George Urban put it, &amp;lsquo;they marched in negative step, but in step all the same.&amp;rsquo; They had their spies, we had ours. They had their files, we had ours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Civil Rights Movement&#39;s Forgotten Radicals</title>
      <link>/posts/2015/03/23/the-civil-rights-movements-forgotten-radicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015/03/23/the-civil-rights-movements-forgotten-radicals/</guid>
      <description>I have a new essay up at Jacobin on continuities of radicalism between the Civil Rights Movement and today&#39;s struggles against racism:
 However devoutly liberals may wish for it, democracy cannot be depoliticized. Political change can only be pursued and maintained by political commitment and engagement. The sacralization of the Civil Rights Movement’s achievements through constitutional jurisprudence is the entombment, not the revivification, of the struggle for racial justice and equality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking on Against the Grain</title>
      <link>/posts/2014/10/28/speaking-on-against-the-grain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014/10/28/speaking-on-against-the-grain/</guid>
      <description>Tune in at 12:00PM PDT to hear me talk with C.S. Soong on Against the Grain about the Supreme Court, Jacobin, and why liberal Court-worship means we can&#39;t have nice things.
Update: You can listen to the audio on Against the Grain&amp;lsquo;s website here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abolish the States</title>
      <link>/posts/2014/08/13/abolish-the-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014/08/13/abolish-the-states/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Abolish the States,&amp;rdquo; my polemic against federalism and &amp;ldquo;states&amp;rsquo; rights,&amp;rdquo; is up at Jacobin. I&#39;ve written before about how federalism frustrates freedom rather than promoting it. Federalism &amp;ndash; the fragmentation of political authority and the preference for subsidiarity over national political equality &amp;ndash; inhibits the consolidation of centralized political institutions and thwarts mass movements seeking comprehensive political change.
As a sort of colloquy on the topic, here are some choice quotes on federalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waiting for SCOTUS</title>
      <link>/posts/2014/06/02/waiting-for-scotus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014/06/02/waiting-for-scotus/</guid>
      <description>I have an essay in the latest issue of Jacobin on liberals&amp;rsquo; preference for crafting policy through judicial review &amp;ndash; rather than pursuing political power through collective action. Liberals have not only abandoned mass politics by embracing the Court, but they have also turned their backs on the radical implications of the (partial and incomplete) successes of mass movements and the expansion of democracy in American political history. It&#39;s a fundamentally antidemocratic posture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Contradictions of Cyberlibertarianism</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/12/09/cyberlibertarianism-as-mystification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/12/09/cyberlibertarianism-as-mystification/</guid>
      <description>In an excellent essay recently posted at Jacobin, David Golumbia calls attention to the reactionary tendency of cyberlibertarian frames on digital culture and politics. Cyberlibertarians&amp;rsquo; preference for viewing all political conflicts as computationally tractable tends to diminish the importance of political participation, and shrouds structures of power rather than illuminates them: &amp;ldquo;computational practices are intrinsically hierarchical and shaped by identification with power.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Hacktivists&amp;rdquo; and digital utopians are practitioners of the kind of neoliberal antipolitics that elides questions of political antagonism in favor of adopting a managerialist posture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance Is Not a Technical Problem With Technical Solutions</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/08/20/surveillance-is-not-a-technical-problem-with-technical-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/08/20/surveillance-is-not-a-technical-problem-with-technical-solutions/</guid>
      <description>Pamela Jones, founder-operator of the indispensible blog Groklaw, has announced that the site will be shuttered because she no longer feels confident using email, citing the recent closure of Lavabit. She would rather be in the position of not having data to hand over in response to a &amp;ldquo;National Security Letter&amp;rdquo; should she ever be presented with one.
It&#39;s hard to fault Jones for acting on a healthy and justified fear of an unconstrained surveillance regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quite Possibly the Best Capsule Summary of the Critique of Political Economy (As Opposed to Economics)</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/07/21/possibly-the-best-capsule-summary-of-political-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/07/21/possibly-the-best-capsule-summary-of-political-economy/</guid>
      <description>From the introduction to Isaak Illich Rubin&amp;lsquo;s Essays on Marx&#39;s Theory of Value:
Political economy does not analyze the material-technical aspect of the capitalist process of production, but its social form, i.e., the totality of production relations which make up the &amp;ldquo;economic structure&amp;rdquo; of capitalism. &amp;hellip; This distinction at the same time defines the method of political economy as a social and historical science. In the variegated and diversified chaos of economic life which represents a combination of social relations and technical methods, this distinction also directs our attention precisely to those social relations among people in the process of production, to those production relations, for which the production technology serves as an assumption or basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Names Aren&#39;t Important: A Panegyric for Iain M. Banks</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/06/19/iain-banks-1954-2013-culture-novels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/06/19/iain-banks-1954-2013-culture-novels/</guid>
      <description>{% blockquote Walter Benjamin http://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/benjamin/1940/history.htm On the Concept of History %} According to Fourier, a beneficent division of social labor would have the following consequences: four moons would illuminate the night sky; ice would be removed from the polar cap; saltwater from the sea would no longer taste salty; and wild beasts would enter into the service of human beings. All this illustrates a labor which, far from exploiting nature, is instead capable of delivering creations whose possibility slumbers in her womb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iain (M.) Banks, 1954–2013</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/06/17/names-arent-important-iain-banks-1954-2013-culture-universe-novels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/06/17/names-arent-important-iain-banks-1954-2013-culture-universe-novels/</guid>
      <description>#Names Aren&#39;t Important: A Panegyric for the Culture
Walter Benjamin, On the Concept of History:
 According to Fourier, a beneficent division of social labor would have the following consequences: four moons would illuminate the night sky; ice would be removed from the polar cap; saltwater from the sea would no longer taste salty; and wild beasts would enter into the service of human beings. All this illustrates a labor which, far from exploiting nature, is instead capable of delivering creations whose possibility slumbers in her womb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Freedom</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/06/11/the-golden-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/06/11/the-golden-freedom/</guid>
      <description>James A. Michener on federalism in Poland They were defending their freedom to neutralize the king; they were defending their freedom to keep the newly built towns subservient to their country areas; they were defending most strongly their freedom to keep their peasants in a state of perpetual serfdom as opposed to the liberties which were being grudgingly won in the western parts of Europe; and they were doing everything reactionary within their power to preserve the advantages they had against the legitimate aspirations of the growing gentry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federalism Against Freedom</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/03/18/federalism-against-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/03/18/federalism-against-freedom/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading Peter Wilson&#39;s The Thirty Years War, and I regret that I didn&#39;t read it sooner. While the book has received no small amount of attention for its contributions to the history of warfare, or of Germany, or central Europe in general, it can also be read as an important contribution to constitutional theory. The study of the constitution of the Holy Roman Empire &amp;ndash; here using the sense of the word &amp;ldquo;constitution&amp;rdquo; in its &amp;ldquo;older&amp;rdquo; sense, that is, as a package of values, norms, and institutions peculiar to a given political community &amp;ndash; can, I argue, furnish insights that are valuable to the study of the constitutional order in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SF, Incluing, and Infodumps</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/12/12/sf-incluing-and-infodumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/12/12/sf-incluing-and-infodumps/</guid>
      <description>Every so often one comes across a corner of the Internet where someone has written, created or shared exactly the kind of thing you were hoping you&#39;d some day come across. I had that experience recently with a blog post defending the use of the expository tactics of &amp;ldquo;infodumping&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;incluing&amp;rdquo; in science fiction:
{% blockquote %} For me, one of the things that fundamentally makes sf, sf, is that it goes out of its way to require more exposition than other literary modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Review, Economic Inequality, and the Power of Money</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/06/25/judicial-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/06/25/judicial-review/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today the Supreme Court refused, in a 5-4 party line vote, to reconsider Citizens United and struck down a century-old Montana law regulating corporate spending in state elections. You can read all about the gory details elsewhere (it&#39;s worth noting that the ruling might not be that much of a setback to proponents of campaign finance reform); but here are my two cents:
First, the Court simply assumed its own facts and basically ignored the Montana legislature&#39;s findings of fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popular Constitutionalism and Political Parties</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/05/31/popular-constitutionalism-and-political-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/05/31/popular-constitutionalism-and-political-parties/</guid>
      <description>Parties as Platforms for Popular Constitutionalism
The major parties in the contemporary U.S. are ideologically polarized and, currently, come closer now than they often have in the past to acting with parliamentary levels of discipline. (Well, alright, maybe only the Republicans are currently capable of acting with a high level of intra-party discipline, to the detriment of Senate comity and federal budget policy.)
We can complain about how (asymmetric) ideological polarization between the two parties is detrimental to democratic politics, to policy-making, to the state of political discourse, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constitutional Dysfunction and Constitutional Criticism</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/05/29/constitutional-dysfunction-constitutional-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/05/29/constitutional-dysfunction-constitutional-criticism/</guid>
      <description>Sanford Levinson has a post on the New York Times&#39;s &amp;ldquo;Campaign Stops&amp;rdquo; blog, in which he presents a condensed version of the argument that he&#39;s been making for the better part of a decade elsewhere: specifically, that the U.S. Constitution is profoundly undemocratic, undermines political equality, and is unnecessarily difficult to amend through electoral politics. It&#39;s a brisk and &amp;ndash; characteristically for Levinson &amp;ndash; entertaining cri de cœur about the need for reviving the &amp;ldquo;democracy&amp;rdquo; part of &amp;ldquo;constitutional democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital Punishment and Popular Constitutionalism</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/05/09/capital-punishment-and-popular-constitutionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/05/09/capital-punishment-and-popular-constitutionalism/</guid>
      <description>I recently led classroom discussions on the Supreme Court&#39;s death penalty rulings in Furman and Gregg. Unsurprisingly, my students weren&#39;t impressed with Furman&amp;lsquo;s mélange of concurrences supporting (for different reasons) the per curiam holding that the capital sentencing in the case was cruel and unusual. In general, students are drawn to absolutes and decisiveness. They want exceptionless rules, unambiguous standards, and, all in all, an ordered universe of constitutional law. To their minds, Furman is a muddle, and Gregg&amp;lsquo;s clarification of its reasoning is scant improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past and Future Popular Constitutionalism</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/27/past-and-future-popular-constitutionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/27/past-and-future-popular-constitutionalism/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently started reading Stephen Engel&#39;s American Politicians Confront the Court: Opposition Politics and Changing Responses to Judicial Power, an historical overview of the conflict between political actors and the Supreme Court over constitutional interpretation. As the title suggests, Engel is more concerned with political leaders acting from within and on behalf of political institutions, parties, and coalitions, and not so much with mass movements on behalf of constitutional change or maintenance (but more on that later).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ninth Amendment and Popular Constitutionalism</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/24/the-ninth-amendment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/24/the-ninth-amendment/</guid>
      <description>While leading a discussion section on Griswold yesterday, I had what has now become a familiar experience: students tend to prefer, by a large margin, Justice Goldberg&#39;s Ninth Amendment-based reasoning to Justice Douglas&#39;s liberty reasoning, insofar as they both identify a constitutional right to privacy. Many students tend to be chary of Douglas&#39;s &amp;ldquo;penumbras&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;emanations,&amp;rdquo; which they see as Lochnerizing &amp;ndash; substantive due process rearing its ugly head. They see Goldberg&#39;s reasoning as the more restrained option, in fact: they think that because he hangs his hat on the Ninth Amendment, he has a firmer textual basis for his argument than Douglas, who relies on a structural reading of the relationships between, and implications of, different rights guarantees, precedents, and principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Lesson on the Difficulty of Reconciling Judicial Supremacy With Democracy</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/19/another-lesson-on-the-difficulty-of-reconciling-judicial-supremacy-with-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/19/another-lesson-on-the-difficulty-of-reconciling-judicial-supremacy-with-democracy/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s a recent article by Slate&#39;s Dahlia Lithwick about a ruling from the DC circuit, in which Judge Janice Rogers Brown writes a concurrence that dwells on an economic libertarian vision of economic liberty. This liberty, despite not being mentioned by name in the Constitution&#39;s text (which conservatives usually think matters in determining whether or not something is a legitimate liberty interest), has allegedly been under constant assault by &amp;ldquo;a democratic process&amp;rdquo; that Brown considers beholden to unnamed &amp;ldquo;powerful groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dwm: a tutorial for beginners</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/17/dwm-a-tutorial-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/17/dwm-a-tutorial-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial explains how to install, set up, and customize dwm. dwm is a window manager for X and the forerunner to xmonad and awesome, among others. As a tiling window manager, it automatically creates, adjusts, and moves windows for you so that you can focus on being productive. This means that it&#39;s equally useful whether you&#39;re using multiple large displays or a small netbook screen; it&#39;s also stable and consumes little by way of system resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Octopress</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/12/switching-to-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/12/switching-to-octopress/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched from using WordPress to power my personal blog to Octopress, and my only regret is not switching sooner. Unlike WordPress, MoveableType, or other CMSes, Octopress doesn&#39;t require any MySQL processes running in the background, or futzing about with databases. It&#39;s a wrapper for Jekyll, which is a Ruby framework for generating blogs as static websites, which are secure, simple and fast.
The advantage of Octopress over Jekyll, from the perspective of a non-developer like me, is that it&#39;s simple and straightforward; all you have to do is download and deploy it with a minimum of fuss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5th Circuit Judge Thinks Criticizing Judicial Supremacy is Beyond the Pale</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/04/criticizing-judicial-supremacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/04/criticizing-judicial-supremacy/</guid>
      <description>President Obama noted on Tuesday that, were the Court to take the &amp;ldquo;unprecedented&amp;rdquo; step of striking down the Affordable Care Act (ACA) as unconstitutional, it would be engaging in exactly the kind of &amp;ldquo;judicial activism&amp;rdquo; that conservatives have been decrying for the better part of half a century. This has prompted a flurry of pearl-clutching and overblown criticism, much of it disingenuous and strictly partisan &amp;ndash; which is of course not news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Political Stability</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/04/03/against-political-stability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/04/03/against-political-stability/</guid>
      <description>It is true that what is settled by custom, though it be not good, yet at least it is fit. And those things which have long gone together are as it were confederate within themselves: whereas new things piece not so well, but though they help by their utility, yet they trouble by their incomformity. Besides, they are like strangers, more admired and less favoured. All this were true, if time stood still, which contrariwise moveth so round that a froward retention of custom is as turbulent a thing as an innovation; and they that reverence too much old times are but a scorn to the new&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>